## SRIKRISHNA BHATTACHARYYA

Bangalore, India, Mob:+91-9740085470, skb\_h@yahoo.com

## **Profile**

With more than 15 years of experience in product development and testing of wireless & radio network protocols(2G/3G/LTE) in various telecom R&D giants such as Motorola, Intel, Infineon, Freescale & Anritsu, I aspire to be a part of challenges, where proven track record of competency development as well as leading, managing & accomplishing complex projects from requirement analysis till field testing would help an organization to build strong teams and meeting their commitments towards short term and long term milestone deliverable.

## **Achievements**

- Successfully managed to bring up ENB components within 10 months with significant Rol (CoQ) whilst having taken over the ownership under challenging circumstances & complex delivery contract with partner.
- Efficient technical communication, collaboration & negotiation across sites enabled initiation of the LTE/VoLTE Verification activities & LTE infrastructure development for the first time at Intel Mobile Communication (IMC), Bangalore.
- Active technical contribution in *team recruitment & competency development f*or LTE-FDD/VoLTE/modem projects in IMC Bangalore & Beijing (initial setup).
- ➤ Team recruitment & their competency development (50+ engineers) through class room training & hands-on 3G stack call flow analysis at Sasken Communication.
- Active participation in validating 3G IRAT conformance with *Anritsu's esteemed customer in Japan* which helped Anritsu to gain confidence & more business.
- Successfully managed to deliver Freescales's Symbian based 3G Modem platform to their customer under competitive deadline.
- Onsite dual RAT validation engagement at COMNEON Germany enabled Aricent (/Flextronics) to open their first UE modem account.
- ➤ As a part of six sigma & CMMI initiative campaign in Motorola, proactive effort in early phase verification engagement enabled reducing the escape defect & hence improved the system test pass rate(70%->95%).

## Certifications

Prince2 Foundation qualified, PMP trained [35HRS PDU]

MS project (MPP), Agile (Scrum) in progress.

# Skills at a glance

- ➤ Interpersonal abilities listening, empathizing & multi-cultural awareness.
- Independently managed large complex projects (majorly UE domain) from inception through design and build through phase completion stage namely integration or field testing.
- Highly focused on bigger picture, drive with passion to meet the short term as well as long term goals.
- Cross functional team work, communication, analytical, problem solving and presentational skills.
- Interface with projects technical & operational team.
- Highly focused on process improvement & adhering to quality policy defined by HQ.
- ➤ EVM based monitoring and controlling the vendor processes, maintaining the risk register.
- Keen to develop innovation, IPs & assets.
- Functional domain experience: 6-7 years.
  - Recruitment, mentoring & inducting engineers into project.
  - Team management, training & development plan, appraisal handling(less exp).
  - New technology, innovation & automation.
  - Deep dive analysis of specs/issues/RFCs.
- Project/Delivery experience: 4-5 years.
  - Project management GANTT update, EVM based project control, Risk management, CAPEX/OPEX, Milestone approval, CoQ, Quality gates, adhering to QA/QC policies etc.
  - Assisted in program mgmt implementation.
  - Modem verification management.
  - Sub-contract management.
  - Status reporting, tracking & dash board management (core team & CCB member).
- Liaison/external communication (OEM/ODM/ Partners/vendors/3rd parties).
- Capable to convince senior management of new ideas, concepts & solution including process improvement.
- Domain 3G, HSPA, LTE, VoLTE/IMS, various Handovers, wireless network interfaces and nodes.
  - Basic understanding of ENB modules and system architecture including MIMO, Cognitive Radio, Micro/ Small Cells, Data Analytics, Cloud, TCP/UDP, 5G [in progress].
- Programming/Scripting understanding— C/C++, J2ME, SQL, TTCN2/3.
- OS & Tools Win8, Linux, MS Office, MSPE, Clearcase, JIRA, DDTS, Time tracker, Doors etc.
- ➤ Debugger gdb, Lauterbach, PureCoverage etc.
- Test simulation Anritsu, Anite, R&S and Agilent (KeySight).
- > Test management Requirement analysis,

## **Education & Credentials**

Master of Engineering : 84% in Telecom (major Computer)

@Jadavpur University [1998-2000].

Bachelor of Engineering: 76% in Electronics & Communication

@ NIT, Durgapur [1992-1996]

# Awards & recognitions

Received several certificates & cash awards in Motorola, Freescale & Sasken Communication for work excellence.

strategising, test planning, test bed setup, test designing, test creation for unit/integration/ sanity/functional/field & documentation.
Test execution & reporting of sanity, functional, conformance, field testing at various phases.

Test automation – PERL based automation for regression suite.

## **Publication & Disclosure**

During ME @ Jadavpur University, Kolkata Paper on "Path finding & obstacle avoidance by a nomadic Robot"-

National level publication

Active support to Prof A.Konar for composing his book on "Artificial Intelligence & Soft Computing".

(http://www.computationalintelligence.net/book/acknowledge/acknowledge.html)

# Work Experience in Detail

CellOS Software Systems Private Limited [earlier known as IndoAust Investments Limited]

LTE Project Manager & Test Manager [Apr'13-May'14]

(Post first phase of component development in India, the integration activities happening in R&D, Melbourne from Apr'2014)

My journey as a Primary PoC for 4G Radio Head HW&SW development & bring up at vendor site started after 5months of its commencement at Bangalore, under challenging circumstances & complex delivery contract.

This was our (CellOS) Off-shore Development setup outside Australia and consisted a team of more than 50 engineers, leads & managers.

The responsibilities of this position were:

- Understanding of ENB architecture, primary modules, interfaces (CPRI, Ethernet), sources of clock i/p and functional behaviour of the whole ENB system.
- Sequencing the development phases (ICD, Schematics, Fabrication, Routing, Gerber, Assembly followed by HW+ SW bring up) & performing an appropriate bottom up/top down estimation to align vendor's bring up timelines with our field trial commitment.
- Regular sync up meeting with vendor SMEs during component selection, schematics design, routing and bring up phases
  for various HW modules namely DSP, BSP, RF+TRX+VSWR, PA,FILTER, MECH and working towards SW design for
  FPGA, Memory & NAND etc.
- Create & maintain a project plan to track vendor's regular progress (7-8 modules 50 resources 8 GATES 10 months).
- Occasional visit to the FAB houses (Chennai & Bangalore) along with vendor to accelerate HW bring up timelines.
- Facilitating monthly reviews with product head during design/ICD, schematics, Routing, Gerber & pre-assembly phases.
- Weekly & monthly GANTT review with vendor team to validate work product delivery & approval of their payment check points.
- Quality exit criteria and EVM based project monitoring & control, usage of metrics to adjust the milestone commitment.
- Conducting a Release readiness review (RRR GO/NOGO) meeting with vendor team prior to accepting any release.
- Co-ordinating with the external developer for the onsite support at our Melbourne R&D centre for the HW & SW
  acceptance testing.
- To analyse & seek approval for the forecasted Capex & Opex requirements.
- To maintain the RISK register & update with probable mitigation (/contingency proposal).
- To initiate & maintain focused discussion related to IPs & Innovation.
- Overseeing the assets handover, NDA signing & structured project closure during next phase handover to our team @MLB.
- Ensure the project closure yields a significant RoI(CoQ) to the program.

Prior to this project I was managing the ramp up activities related to Business Intelligence IBM Netezza based Analytics dev.

#### **Intel Mobile Communication**

#### Member of Technical Staff [Jun'11-Mar'13]

- Inter-site communication, collaboration and negotiation enabled IMC verification team to involve in early verification activities.
- Led VoLTE (LTE+IMS) bring up activities & test infrastructure development.
- Worked with functional manager for team development & budget planning (Capex & Opex) for infra development.
- Vendor communication & test development for platform verification and validation (Anritsu, Anite, R&S, Agilent).

## **Anritsu Limited**

## Senior R&D Support Engineer [Aug'10-May'11]

Backend product support for ticket handling and customer interaction; LTE conformance (IRAT) support to customer.

## Sasken Communication Technologies Limited

## Manager Project - Product Testing [Oct'09-July'10]

- To build competency on wireless architecture and protocols for a team of 50+ people.
- Reinstated Sasken's 3G stack for the competency development.
- Recruitment, mentoring and developing the product field testing team.
- Participated in the performance appraisal & career development.

## **Freescale Semiconductor India Limited**

#### Modem validation & verification lead/PM (PMO)[Feb'06-May'09]

(Freescale, Bangalore closed down their operations in May 2009)

- Complete ownership of symbian based 3gpp rel5 modem platform validation and verification activities.
- Inter-team and intra-team co-ordination for a team of 20-25 people in India and France.
- Responsible for adhering to QA standard and participating in the quality audit (internal & external).

# <u>Aricent Technologies (earlier known as Flextronics Software System)</u> Technical Lead[Feb'04-Feb'06]

- Onsite test development support at Infineon (Comneon), Germany for 10 months.
- Led a team of 8 people for functional test planning for IMS-SCSCF node & GAN interfaces

#### **Motorola India Electronics Limited**

Senior Software Engineer [Apr'2000-Feb'2004], through Campus of M.E.

- Developed various scripts for 3gpp compliant handsets; mentoring & team building.
- Actively contributed for GSM-AMPS protocol development(C) and integration activities.
- Actively contributed for Motorola's Test platform implementation (C++).

#### TATA Jamshedpur

#### Graduate Engineer [Jan1997-Aug1998] through Campus

Programming & maintenance of state of the art Lucent Digital Exchange was having capabilities of 2000.

#### **ALTOS India**

## Graduate Engineer Trainee [Jun1996-Jan1997] through Campus

• Engaged in Dell's Mother Board verification (op-code driven) during the assembly process.